<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" standalone="no"?>
<!--
  Copyright (C) 2019 RuleKit Development Team
  
  This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the
  GNU Affero General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3
  of the License, or (at your option) any later version.
   
  This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without
  even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU
   Affero General Public License for more details.
   
  You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License along with this program.
  If not, see http://www.gnu.org/licenses/.
-->
<operatorHelp lang="en_EN">    
   <group>
      <key>rulekit</key>
      <name>RuleKit</name>
   </group>    
   
   <operator>
	   <key>expert_rule_generator</key>
	   <name>RuleKit Generator</name>
	   <synopsis>RuleKit generator</synopsis>
	   <help>
	   Generates classification, regression, or survival rules.
	   </help>
	</operator> 
	
	 <operator>
	   <key>rule_performance</key>
	   <name>RuleKit Performance</name>
	   <synopsis>RuleKit performance evaluator</synopsis>
	   <help>
	   Evaluates performance of rule models.
	   </help>
	</operator> 
	
	
	<operator>
        <name>Write ARFF (RapidMiner 5)</name>
        <synopsis>Writes the values of all examples into an ARFF-file.
        </synopsis>
        <help>Writes values of all examples into an ARFF file which can be
            used by the machine learning library Weka. The ARFF format is
            described in the &lt;i&gt;ArffExampleSource&lt;/i&gt; operator which
            is able to read ARFF files to make them usable with RapidMiner.
        </help>
    	<key>write_arff_rm5</key>
	</operator>
	
	
	<operator>
        <name>Read ARFF (RapidMiner 5)</name>
        <synopsis>This operator can read arff files.</synopsis>
        <help>&lt;p&gt;This operator can read ARFF files known from the
            machine learning library Weka. An ARFF (Attribute-Relation File
            Format) file is an ASCII text file that describes a list of instances
            sharing a set of attributes. ARFF files were developed by the Machine
            Learning Project at the Department of Computer Science of The
            University of Waikato for use with the Weka machine learning
            software.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;ARFF files have two distinct sections.
            The first section is the Header information, which is followed the
            Data information. The Header of the ARFF file contains the name of
            the relation (@RELATION, ignored by RapidMiner) and a list of the
            attributes, each of which is defined by a starting @ATTRIBUTE
            followed by its name and its type.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Attribute
            declarations take the form of an orderd sequence of @ATTRIBUTE
            statements. Each attribute in the data set has its own @ATTRIBUTE
            statement which uniquely defines the name of that attribute and it's
            data type. The order the attributes are declared indicates the column
            position in the data section of the file. For example, if an
            attribute is the third one declared all that attributes values will
            be found in the third comma delimited column.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The
            possible attribute types are:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;numeric&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;integer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;real&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;{nominalValue1,nominalValue2,...}&lt;/code&gt;
            for nominal attributes&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;string&lt;/code&gt; for nominal attributes
            without distinct nominal values (it is however recommended to use the
            nominal definition above as often as possible)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;date [date-format]&lt;/code&gt; (currently not
            supported by RapidMiner)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Valid
            examples for attribute definitions are &lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;code&gt;@ATTRIBUTE petalwidth REAL&lt;/code&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;code&gt;@ATTRIBUTE class
            {Iris-setosa,Iris-versicolor,Iris-virginica}&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The ARFF Data section of the file contains the data
            declaration line @DATA followed by the actual example data lines.
            Each example is represented on a single line, with carriage returns
            denoting the end of the example. Attribute values for each example
            are delimited by commas. They must appear in the order that they were
            declared in the header section (i.e. the data corresponding to the
            n-th @ATTRIBUTE declaration is always the n-th field of the example
            line). Missing values are represented by a single question mark, as
            in:&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;code&gt;4.4,?,1.5,?,Iris-setosa&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A
            percent sign (%) introduces a comment and will be ignored during
            reading. Attribute names or example values containing spaces must be
            quoted with single quotes ('). Please note that the sparse ARFF
            format is currently only supported for numerical attributes. Please
            use one of the other options for sparse data files provided by
            RapidMiner if you also need sparse data files for nominal
            attributes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Please have a look at the Iris example
            ARFF file provided in the data subdirectory of the sample directory
            of RapidMiner to get an idea of the described data format.&lt;/p&gt;
        </help>
    <key>read_arff_rm5</key>
</operator>
	
	<!--

   <operator>
	    <key>rule_translator</key>
	    <name>Rule translator</name>
	    <synopsis>Rule translator</synopsis>
	    <help>
	    Translates rules from RapidMiner to Disesor format.
	    </help>
	</operator>
	
	-->
   
</operatorHelp>
